Alpha and Omega: The Big Fureeze is a family,
animation film directed by Tim Maltby.
Kate and Humphrey head out into the woods to look for food to stock up on for
winter, and they leave their three pups with their parents.
But the pups and the rest of the pack must venture out in search
of them after the duo get caught in a blizzard.
Kate / Stinky (voice), played by Kate Higgins.
Humphrey / Bear 1 (voice), played by Ben Diskin.
Claudette (voice), played by Marieve Herington.
Runt (voice), played by Debi Derryberry.
Paddy / Marcel (voice), played by Christopher Corey Smith.
Alpha and Omega is a 2010 American animated romantic comedy
adventure film directed by Anthony Bell and Ben Gluck.
Starring the voices of Justin Long, Hayden Panettiere, Dennis Hopper, Danny Glover and Christina Ricci, the
film was written by Christopher Denk and Steve Moore, based on a story by Moore and Gluck.
The film sets around two young Rocky Mountain wolves named Kate (Panettiere) and Humphrey (Long)
who fall in love with each other, but are on the opposite ends of their pack.
However, when Kate and Humphrey learn that they got relocated to Idaho for repopulation, they must work
together to get back to Jasper National Park before a war slowly begins to emerge between both packs.
The film premiered at the Toronto International Film Festival on September 8, 2010, and
was released nationwide in 2-D and 3-D on September 17, 2010, by Lionsgate.
Alpha and Omega was a box-office success, grossing $50.5 million against a budget of
$20 million, but received generally negative reviews from critics.
Despite its negative reception, however, it has received a cult following.
The film was dedicated to Hopper, as he died from prostate
cancer four months before it was released.
The film eventually turned into a franchise of 7 direct-to-video sequels including Alpha
and Omega 2: A Howl-iday Adventure, which was released on October 8, 2013.
Another sequel, The Great Wolf Games, was released on March 25, 2014.
The Legend of the Saw Tooth Cave was released on September 23, 2014.
Family Vacation was released to DVD on August 4, 2015.
Dino Digs was released on DVD and Digital HD on May 10, 2016.
It was followed by The Big Fur-eeze, which was released on November 8, 2016.
The final installment, Journey to Bear Kingdom was
released on DVD and Digital HD on May 9, 2017.
The film explores themes of wolf, cartoon, christmas.